# Adi Triono

**IT Support** 

## **CONTACT**





milikadi@gmail.com

Jalan Kramat II No.51 Kebayoran, South Jakarta 12220 Indonesia

+62 856 100 4963

www.linkedin.com/in/adi-triono-59724827

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced in the IT field with more than ten years of work experience in leading national companies in information media, two years working in a company engaged in providing energy and support services. One year in the world's largest multinational e-commerce companies, One year working in the company global leader in biosciences and sensorial, able working in a multicultural environment, strong analytical thinking and technical ability to deliver *technology-based* solutions for business.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Essence Indonesia on May 2020 - Feb 2021

IT Support Assigned in leading International biosciences and sensorial, Essence Indonesia Company is an integrated IFF company based in the USA. Responsible for daily IT operations and to all hardware equipment, to ensure that software and applications run well and provide reliable end-user support.

Satisfaction with users who use the PC and all IT hardware also application software and infrastructure running well based on the SLA, ensure the global policy runs in accordance with central regulations.

# Indy Digital Investama on March 2018 - May 2020

IT Infrastructure Engineer and Application Support Assigned in leading national Company Indika Energy Tbk are an integrated energy company based in Indonesia that is primarily engaged in providing energy support services. Responsible for daily IT operations and ensuring that software and applications run well and provide reliable end-user.

Satisfaction with users who use the application software and infrastructure running well based on the SLA, Improve SLA performance in end-user service delivery also problems related to application and infrastructure/network.

# China Telecom Indonesia on March 2017 - March 2018

IT On-Site Engineer Assigned in leading e-commerce company Alibaba as an onsite engineer at Alibaba's cloud datacentre in Indonesia. Supporting technical issues and maintaining sustainability in the data center environment. Supports and provides some oversight of IT services and support functions following Service Level Agreements for areas of responsibility.

Successfully made a major contribution for the company to achieve its goals. Can manage work independently by following the SLA, creating and maintaining relevant technical documentation, effectively solving problems in the data center environment, and interacting with vendors, contractors, and technicians.

## Kompas Gramedia Group on June 2006 - February 2017

IT Helpdesk and Networks admin Assigned in leading news and media company Warta Kota Newspapers. Responsible for daily IT operations and ensuring that software and applications run well and provide reliable end-user support including hardware and software, configuring and maintain Network infrastructure including Internet connection and Cross office connection.

Successfully made satisfaction with users who use IT environment or PC also the application and infrastructure running well based on the SLA, Improve SLA performance in end-user service delivery also problems related to application and infrastructure/network.

## **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

STMIK Swadharma Bachelor degree majoring information system in 2005, Jakarta

- Implementing and installation Windows server 2003 in 2006, Jakarta
- International Language Program English language courses in 2008, Jakarta
- Cisco Internetworking Course, Bit-Education in 2008, Jakarta
- Mikrotik RouterOS Training, Citraweb Nusa Infomedia in 2011, Jakarta

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Operating system: MS DOS, Windows 7, Windows 10, Mac OS, Windows server 2010, Linux
- Applications infrastructure: Active Directory service (DNS, WINS, DHCP), MS Exchange 2010, ITIL Symantec Altiris
- Virtualization: Virtual Box, VMware vSphere ESXi 5
- **Applications network:** TCP/IP, switching and dynamic routing (VLAN, Proxy, QOS, Firewall, VPN, Queue tree, simple queue), WAN internetworking, Voip Ericsson / LG
- Antivirus Handle: Symantec (Altiris, SEE, Ghost), ESET smart security, SMADAV
- Hardware: Dell/Hp/Lenovo Laptop/Desktop, Intermec RFscanner, Zebra Printer
- Programming language: CLI cisco, php, IIS, apache web server, SQL server, MySQL
- Desktop applications software: MS Word, MS Excel, MS power point, MS outlook, MS Teams, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe CS.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Indonesia: Very good
English: Good